Guide to the George Tselos Papers TAM.831
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
George Tselos Papers
1911-1998
1957-1982
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tselos, George D.
Tselos, Helen
TAM.831
1.5 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes
George Tselos (1939- ) is a labor historian and a retired National Park Service archivist. Tselos was an early member of the Socialist Worker Party. The George Tselos Papers (dated 1911-1998; bulk 1957-1982) consists of materials created and collected by Tselos documenting his political engagements and professional career as an archivist and labor historian. Through correspondence, ephemera, publications, and original writings the collection documents Tselos' student activism in the 1960s and engagement with the Socialist Workers Party, as well as his academic research and writings on disarmament, the 1939 WPA strike, and the history of trade unions. The collection also includes personal correspondence, a portion of which is between Tselos and his family regarding his developing radical thought as a student activist.
Scope and Contents
The George Tselos Papers (dated 1911-1998; bulk 1957-1982) consists of materials created and collected by Tselos documenting his political engagements and professional career as an archivist and labor historian. Through correspondence, ephemera, publications, and original writings the collection documents Tselos' student activism in the 1960s and engagement with the Socialist Workers Party, as well as his academic research and writings on disarmament, the 1939 WPA strike, and the history of trade unions. The collection also includes personal correspondence, a portion of which is between Tselos and his family regarding his developing radical thought as a student activist.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Helena Tselos in November 2023; the accession number associated with this gift is 2024.017.
Biographical Note
George Tselos (1939- ) is a labor historian and a retired National Park Service archivist. Tselos was an early member of the Socialist Worker Party.
Archivists; Labor movement -- Historiography; Labor -- History; Historians; Cuba -- Foreign Relations -- United States.; Disarmament.; Socialism; Strikes and lockouts.; Tselos, Helen; Socialist Workers Party
- George Tselos Biographical Information, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
- WPA Strike -- Mid-America Conference on History Paper, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Stanley Weir and Longshoremen's Suit, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Local Ephemera, 1960-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cary, Lee, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters from Folks, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Disarmament, Test Ban, 1960-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- WPA Strike -- Text of Portions of Woodrum Act, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- WPA Strike -- Letter from Geldman, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Frank Lovell, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Articles and Letters, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "The Appraisal of Labor Union Grievance Records", after 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Labor History, 1911-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Oral History Interviews with Workers -- Contemporary Labor Problems, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- American Working Class History Project, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Schniderman, Saul ("Talkin' Union"), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Boles Manuscript, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Sorbonne Correspondence about AFL-CIO Proceedings, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence -- Leslie S. Hough, Director Ohio Labor History Project, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence -- George Parkinson, Curator West Virginia Collection, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Exhibition Technique, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence -- Personal, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Memos -- Internal, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence -- Dom Capeci, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Society of American Archivists Meetring, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence -- Philip A. Korth, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence and Ephemera, 1957-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- WPA Strike -- Murphy Collection Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Cuba -- Refugees, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Privacy, Right of, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- NCLIS, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- History Education, Society for, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Cuba -- Travel Ban, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Cuba -- General, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Cuba -- "Tractors for Freedom", undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Student Strikes, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
- Personal -- Campus Activism, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Notebooks, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 6-8)